Finding Aid for Michigan Library Association records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sections, 1975-1989
  - Children's Services
    - Minutes
      - 1982-1983 (Box 39)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 39)
      - 1986 (Box 39)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 39)
    - Nominations, 1984-1988 (Box 39)
    - Officers and Committee Members, 1979-1989 (Box 39)
    - Position Papers, 1988-1989 (Box 39)
    - Principles for Planning Children's Services in Public Libraries in Michigan, 1985-1988 (Box 39)
    - Research and Assessment, 1981-1985 (Box 39)
    - Share Your Success, 1981-1987 (Box 39)
    - Share Your Success Publications I and II, 1979; 1982 (Box 39)
    - Spring Institute
      - 1981 (Box 39)
      - 1982 (Box 39)
      - 1983 (Box 39)
      - 1984 (Box 39)
      - 1985 (Box 40)
      - 1986 (Box 40)
      - 1987 (Box 40)
      - 1988 (Box 40)
    - Summer Reading Program
      - 1986-1988 (Box 40)
      - 1988 (Box 40)
  - Community College, 1983-1984 (Box 40)
  - Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 40)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1978-1988 (Box 40)
  - Continuing Education (Box 40)
  - Committee Information, 1983-1984
    - Continuing Education Unit (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 40)
    - Fall Conference, 1988 (Box 40)
    - Finances, 1985/86 (Box 40)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1978-1988 (Box 40)
    - Membership Rosters and Officers and Committee Members (Box 40)
    - Minutes, 1980-1988 (Box 40)
    - Programs and Workshops, 1987-1988 (Box 40)
    - Reports, 1977-1988 (Box 40)
  - Cooperative, 1981-1984 (Box 40)
  - Council of Michigan Library Organizations, 1980 (Box 40)
  - Documents, 1981-1984 (Box 40)
  - Educational Foundation
    The Educational Foundation is a section of the MLA was started in 1980 with the purpose of giving librarians the chance to participate in continuing education programs. However, in 1985 the Educational Foundation was dissolved. Their funds were transferred to the MLA. The dissolution is well documented.
    - Constitution and Bylaws, 1985 (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 41)
    - Dissolution, 1981-1985 (Box 41)
    - Finances, 1981-1985 (Box 41)
    - Fundraising, 1981-1985 (Box 41)
    - Grants, 1981-1985 (Box 41)
    - Incorporation, 1980-1984 (Box 41)
    - Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 41)
    - Nominations, 1983 (Box 41)
  - Friends
    - Awards, 1986 (Box 41)
    - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1985 (Box 41)
    - Finances, 1979-1983 (Box 41)
    - For Friends From Friends Publication, 1979; 1980 (Box 41)
    - Goals and Objectives (Box 41)
    - History (Box 41)
    - List of Friends of the Library in Michigan, 1977-1982 (Box 41)
      The mission of the Friends of the library is to create and maintain an association of persons from outside the librarian community who are interested in libraries and wish to their support. The strongest documentation is found in the section's history, membership lists, minutes, public relations and newsletters.
    - Membership Rosters, 1980-1984 (Box 41)
    - Minutes, 1964-1987 (Box 41)
    - Newsletters, 1965-1985 (Box 41)
    - Public Relations (Box 41)
    - Reports, 1965-1984 (Box 41)
    - Speakers Bureau (Box 41)
    - Workshops and Programs, 1977-1984 (Box 41)
  - Government Documents, 1984 (Box 41)
  - Insurance Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 41)
  - Intellectual Freedom
    - Annual Reports, 1982-1984 (Box 41)
    - Clippings (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1988 (Box 41)
    - Incident Reports (Box 41)
    - Issues (Box 41)
    - Goals and Objectives (Box 41)
    - Membership Rosters (Box 41)
    - Minutes, 1982-1988 (Box 41)
    - Support Packets (Box 41)
    - Three Rivers, Michigan, 1982 (Box 41)
  - Junior Members, 1982-1984 (Box 41)
  - Legislative (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 42)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1977-1978 (Box 42)
    - Michigan Legislation (Box 42)
    - Membership Rosters, 1976-1984 (Box 42)
    - Minutes, 1976-1985 (Box 42)
    - Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
  - Let's Talk About It
    - Publication, 1986 (Box 42)
    - Interim Performance and Financial Report, 1985 (Box 42)
  - Let's Talk About It Michigan, 1984-87 (Box 42)
  - Library Education, 1983 (Box 42)
  - Library Law
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1982-1983 (Box 42)
    - Membership Rosters, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
    - Michigan Legislation, 1984 (Box 42)
    - Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 42)
    - Reports, 1961; 1985 (Box 42)
  - Library of Michigan, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
  - Management and Administrative, 1986-1988 (Box 42)
  - Manuscripts Repositories, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Media, 1984-1988 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Interorganization Council on Continuing Library Education
    The Michigan Interorganization Council on Continuing Library Education section encourages and facilitates statewide planning for professional development and the continuing education of library and information service personnel. The material on proposals and grants and the section's correspondence depict their activities.
    - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 42)
    - Finances (Box 42)
    - Membership Rosters, 1983 (Box 42)
    - Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 42)
    - Needs Assessment, 1978-1979 (Box 42)
    - Programs, 1978-1984 (Box 42)
    - Proposals and Grants, 1977-1984 (Box 42)
    - Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
  - Midwest Federation of Library Associations, 1983-1984 (Box 42)
  - Nominating, 1978-1987 (Box 42)
  - Northern Libraries, 1980-1985 (Box 42)
  - Preservation, 1986-1989 (Box 43)
  - Public Libraries
    - Correspondence, 1982-1984; 1988 (Box 43)
    - Finances, 1983 (Box 43)
    - Membership Rosters, 1982-1983 (Box 43)
    - Minutes, 1979-1988 (Box 43)
    - Reports, 1982-1985 (Box 43)
    - Workshops and Programs, 1982-1988 (Box 43)
  - Public Policy, 1986-1988 (Box 43)
  - Public Relations, 1978-1988 (Box 43)
  - Reference, 1981-1988 (Box 43)
  - Rural Libraries, 1985-1987 (Box 43)
  - School, 1982-1985 (Box 43)
  - Specialized Services, 1982-1988 (Box 43)
  - State Library, 1981 (Box 43)
  - Technical Services, 1983-1988 (Box 43)
  - Telecommunications, 1981-1984 (Box 43)
  - Test, 1984 (Box 43)
  - Young Adult
    - Awards, 1984-1988 (Box 43)
    - Constitution and Bylaws, 1984 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 43)
    - Finances, 1983-1988 (Box 43)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1983-1984 (Box 43)
    - Grant Proposal, 1980-1982 (Box 43)
    - Membership Rosters, 1979-1986 (Box 43)
    - Minutes, 1974-1987 (Box 43)
    - Reports, 1982-1984 (Box 43)
    - Workshops and Programs, 1977-1988 (Box 43)
    - YA Program Sourcebook and Basic Paperback List, 1978 (Box 43)
- County Libraries
  This material on county libraries was received in 1990 from the MLA who obtained it from the Jackson District Library. The memorandum that accompanied the material is located in the first folder. The series is comprised of information concerning the running of county libraries during and immediately following World War II. Of research interest are the materials dealing with activities relating to the war post-war planning. This information is best documented in minutes, correspondence and workshop records.
  - Bookmobile, 1947 (Box 44)
  - Civilian Defense, undated (Box 44)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1946 (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 44)
  - County Library Law, 1937 (Box 44)
  - Finances, 1942-1948 (Box 44)
  - Goals and Objectives, undated (Box 44)
  - Kellogg Foundation, 1946 (Box 44)
  - Membership Rosters, 1944-1951 (Box 44)
  - Minutes, 1942-1951 (Box 44)
  - Penal Fines, 1947 (Box 44)
  - Photograph of meeting, 1948 (Box 44)
  - Post-war Planning, 1945 (Box 44)
  - Reports, 1942-1944; 1950-1951 (Box 44)
  - Resolutions, 1946 (Box 44)
  - Rural Sociology, 1948 (Box 44)
  - Standards, 1947; 1950-1951 (Box 44)
  - State Aid, 1943; 1948-1949 (Box 44)
  - Survey of County Library Users, 1946-1948 (Box 44)
  - Tri-State Library Extension, 1948 (Box 44)
  - Trustee Roster, undated (Box 44)
  - War Bond Drive, 1944 (Box 44)
  - Workshops and Programs, 1947-1949 (Box 44)
- 1993 Accession, 1977-1991
  - Executive board minutes, 1981-1983 (Box 45)
  - General information notebooks (Box 45)
    (constitution/bylaws, policies/procedures, directory, etc.)
  - Intellectual Freedom Committee
    - Activities, 1985 (Box 45)
    - Chronological file, 1977-1986; 7 folders (Box 45)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986; 4 folders (Box 45)
    - Minutes, 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Management and Administration Forum
    - Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 45)
    - Notebook, 1989-1991; 1 volumes (in 1 folder) (Box 45)
      (includes minutes in part)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Policies and Procedures Manuals, 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Public Policy Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 45)